Nature and Use of Performance Baselines
Welcome to this session on baselines.
Very interesting. You'll recall, we talked about the role of measurement.
Now, we’re going to talk about the idea of a baseline. A numerical baseline.
And to begin, it may seem kind of funny a first way to start this,
but we are going to start with the idea of a need. What is a need?
Well let’s take for example some scale of measurement. Some quantity called Y.
An outcome. Remember, that Y function of X.
What we’re looking at, is the scale of Y.
And on that scale, what we’re going to say is that this is the is condition.
This is where we currently are assessed. That's our baseline.
Kind of like that is condition.
So, maybe this over here is where we
ought to be. That's the goal.
So, we have a baseline and we have a goal. The difference between
the ought and the is, or  the difference between the baseline and the goal can be symbolized
by the Greek symbol Delta. Which means change. Which means difference, if you will.
That is called need.
Need is merely a gap.
It's a gap between what we perceive or measure of what is,
and what we believe ought to be.
So, when we measure it. We make that verifiable and repeatable and confirmable.
Between the is and the ought, so that we can quantify the need.
In this case, like a customer's need.
The customer has a certain performance characteristic
called Y out there. Whether it's a commercial Y or an industrial Y.
Y could be in the commercial world the amount of time it takes to resolve a customer complaint.
Y could be the temperature of the solder.
Y can be anything that the customer wants. That the customer must have.
So this is like a specification. It's a standard.
It's what the customer expects. It's an expectation.
It's a goal. It’s what ought to be.
And over here, off course, we have coming up. What is.
It’s what is and what ought. And the difference is the gap. That's a need.
Now, what's critical to defining need, you can see, is two things. Absolutely critical.
You have to have a baseline and you have to have a goal. An expectation.
If you don't have a baseline and you don't have a goal, how can you have a need?
The gap would be undefined. And therefore, the need is undefined.
So, you can start to see now, that all of this stuff begins to blend together.
The idea of a baseline, the idea of a need, and gap.
The idea that Y is a function of X. The idea of specifications. The idea of baselining.
The idea of Six Sigma. All this begins to blend together over time,
into an operative philosophy. A system by which we manage the business
and look at life and look at our processes and our customers.
And gauge how we get better at doing things. Again, this is all dependent upon measurement,
and Y is a function of X, and our ability to find baselines, and so on.
This is a way we set out roadmaps of how to get better. Absolutely essential.
Thank you for choosing SSMI.